Hey everyone, thanks for listening to
the Grow Your Life podcast. My name is
Jeremiah Kowski. On this podcast, I talk
about ways for you to grow your life,
your business, get more clients, and
make more money online. Today, I want to
talk about something I think we can all
resonate with. If you're a coach or
mentor, you look at how you can help
people. What can they do better? What
can they accomplish better to help them
reach their goals? What's the changes
they can make in their life? What this
does is it allow it it creates a
situation where we we end up becoming
introspectively
perfectionistic
ourselves and I myself have allowed
perfectionism for so long to keep me
from doing the things that I know that I
should be doing. It's been it's held me
back from being able to launch offers in
my business and have the kind of impact
that I want to create many times over.
It's not something that I'm proud of,
but it's something that I know I
struggle with. And so, I've had to
develop some frameworks to realize, hey,
this isn't helping me. And so, I want
you to understand what is perfectionism.
How does it look in business? Well, it's
it's that thing where you're like, I'm
not going to put myself out there. I'm
not going to launch this course or this
coaching program because it's not ready
yet, because my marketing isn't good
enough, because I'm not going to say it
good enough, because I'm not showing up
perfectly. And we end up keeping
ourselves from putting ourselves out
there, procrastinating, delaying, and it
actually creates burnout in our lives.
We end up burning out, trying to do the
perfect thing without actually making
progress. And this is exactly what
happens. I've dealt with this myself.
There's a lot of root causes behind why
this comes in. It could be a fear of
failure. It could be an all or nothing
mindset. It could be you're
overanalyzing the situation. And so what
we have to realize is that this is not
helping us. It's not helping you reach
your goals. It's not helping you
progress forward. And so we have to take
a step back and look at this. There's a
three-part framework that you can do to
help you break free from perfectionism.
Number one, figure out how to shift from
a perfect or nothing mindset. Realize
that taking action is better than
getting everything perfect. Learn to
embrace mistakes. See them as a teaching
experience for you, something that is
going to teach you how to improve. And
then next, set realistic expectations.
Realize perfection is unattainable. It's
not something that we can attain that we
can achieve. And so it's okay if things
are imperfect. You might see a version
of how you want things to be done, how
you want them to go, and they're not
going that way. And you might feel like,
well, if only I just did everything
better, then things would go better. But
the problem is is that that is a fallacy
of a mindset. It's a way of thinking
that is keeping you stuck because you're
always pursuing the better that you
could possibly be doing. And so what you
got to learn to do is take imperfect
action. Launch that program when it's
not ready yet. Put it out there to
people when it's halfway
done. Get things good enough to be able
to make it public. And you got to
replace the mindset of perfectionism
around a mindset of let's take action at
all cost, not let's try to make it
perfect at all costs.
You know, there's a lot of advice that's
given by very successful people around
perfectionism. But I'll tell you this, a
lot of the people giving that those
advice, they're making hundreds of
millions or billions of dollars, the
ones that are actually giving it to you.
And that's not what got them there
because they started with a dream, with
a vision, with the intuition inside of
them and listening to the voice, the
still small voice that's inside of them
to take
action. Realize that a perfect outcome
is never going to happen. And so set a
starting line and a finish line to get
as good as you can to put something out
there. Focus on the big picture, the
larger vision at hand that you have and
celebrate your progress. Progress over
perfection. Progress over trying to make
everything right, quote unquote. It's
okay to mess up. It's okay to try things
out. It's okay to put yourself out
there. Even if things are
imperfect, you got to learn how to shift
your thinking, have realistic
expectations for how things are going,
what's actually happening, accept those
things, and take imperfect action. And
so to be able to apply this, I want to
encourage
you start with figuring out what are the
things that I've been putting off or
procrastinating in my life and my
business lately.
What have I been not doing that I know
that I need to do? What are the things
that I know could move the needle
forward for me, but I've been
waiting and letting those things pass me
by because I'm trying to make it better
or improve the
outcome. Get it out of your mind that
there's a that that success comes by
doing everything perfect. That somehow
that's what produces the results in your
life. It's not
actually doing something, taking action
in some strategic way is what produces
the best results for you. You know, I
find way too often people get caught up
in this trap of
perfectionism. Especially if they
increase their income to a certain
level, they think that, okay, now I got
to do everything perfect to sustain it.
Or if they're struggling with their
income, they also feel like if I did
everything perfect, things would come
together for me. realize as somebody who
dealt with that and as somebody who's
gone on to build a sevenf figureure
business, it's only hurting you. It's
only killing you and you got to cut it
out. You got to learn and realize it's
not helping you. It's not a success
strategy. It might be used to be years
ago for you to survive. You've developed
a survival mechanism in your nervous
system based on perfectionism. But
realize it's better to take action and
to pick up the pieces as you go than to
need to start perfectly every single
time. All right, listen. If you've
enjoyed this, share this podcast with
somebody. Make sure to leave a like,
rate it, and follow. Every week we
launch new episodes of this podcast. If
you are a coach, mentor, or trainer, and
you want to get more clients online, my
Wealthy Coach Academy program is where I
work with you. come alongside you
personally to guide and direct you
through exactly what to do to get more
clients. From your ads to your sales
copy to all the different ways of
utilizing social media and the stuff
that can make your brain spin like
webinars and challenges and videos and
creating a sales pitch that's not sleazy
or slimy. If you want to know how to do
that and actually get clients in an
ethical, high integrity way, that's what
my Wealthy Coach Academy does. I'd love
to see you become a part of it. Click
the link in the description below.
That'll get you started. We'll talk
soon. Have a good one, everybody.
[Music]
[Applause]